Hello English nerds, welcome back
to English Pod, my name is Marco.
And I'm Erica.
And today we're going
to be looking at English
slang and informal
words used in the 1980s.
So this is the next part
of our decades dialogues.
Exactly.
So the 1980s, maybe for many of our
listeners, is a little bit more familiar.
And there are a lot of phrases and a lot
of words that were born in this decade.
And we still use them today.
So we're going to learn those
words and phrases in this dialogue.
But before we start, we need
to preview a couple of words.
So let's go now to vocabulary preview.
vocabulary preview.
So one of the words that we're
going to hear in our dialogue is ride.
Is that your ride?
So a ride.
Normally, we know this
word as a verb, right?
Right.
To ride a bicycle.
In this context, it's an informal
way of referring to your car.
So a ride is a car.
Yeah.
So I just bought a new ride.
All right.
Well, maybe you'll take me
for a ride and you're a new ride.
And you're new ride.
Yeah.
All right.
And we're also going to be
looking at this word, loaded.
He's loaded.
So if you are loaded, you're really rich.
You have a lot of money.
You are loaded with money.
So loaded and ride.
Those are our two words
for vocabulary preview.
And well, let's listen to our 1980s
dialogue and see what happens.
Jim, what's up, man?
Charlie, is that your ride?
It's what ugly, dude.
Don't be at airhead.
This is a 1969 Chevy Impala.
I just need to fix it up a bit.
In a couple of months, this
baby is going to be wicked.
Not even.
Check it out.
Now, that's a fresh ride.
Well, too bad, the driver's a major dweeb.
Anyone can have a car like that
if their daddy's loaded like his.
He's coming this way, be cool.
Hey, guys, what do you
think of my automobile?
Isn't it bad to the bun?
Word.
The ladies are going to
be lining up to get with you
when they see you
driving around in that car.
You really think so.
For sure.
Awesome.
Psych, you totally fell for it.
You're a real scumbag, Charlie.
When I do the nasty with the prom
queen, we'll see who has a last laugh.
Dude, don't have a cow.
All right, so typical high school
students of the decade, right?
Definitely very, very 80s.
Very 80s.
And well, of course, you
always have the situation
with the cool kids and
maybe the kids that are
not so cool and they're
making fun of him, right?
Yeah, but they use some really cool words.
So let's look at them
now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
All right, so the first word that
we saw in language takeaway
and was really interesting,
this word, but ugly.
It's but ugly.
That car is but ugly.
So when something is but
ugly, it's really ugly, right?
It's very ugly, it's not
just ugly, it's very ugly.
And what it would butt
is like from your bottom.
From your bottom, yeah.
So he said the car was
but ugly and the other
guy answered by saying,
hey, don't be an airhead.
An airhead.
Don't be an airhead.
So an airhead is someone
with air in their head.
In their head.
So they're not very smart.
They've got no brain.
So he said, don't be an airhead.
Don't be such an idiot.
Mhm. All right.
Now for the third word, he
described his car as being wicked.
It's wicked.
Wicked, that's wicked.
It's gonna be wicked.
Okay, so this is a very 80s
way of saying it's gonna be cool.
Yep.
It's gonna be awesome.
It's gonna be wicked.
All right.
And now when they
saw another car pulling up
a new car, he described
it as a fresh ride.
It's a fresh ride.
Now we understand
that ride is a car, right?
So a fresh ride.
It's another way of saying cool.
Okay, so kind of similar, wicked and fresh.
Yeah, now finally at
the end of our dialogue,
they said, you're a
real scumbag, Charlie.
So this word scumbag is interesting.
You're a scumbag.
A scumbag.
Yeah, it's interesting.
And it's still used today, I would say.
Yep.
So when someone is a scumbag,
they're just really not a nice person.
Yeah, they're not nice or they're
not maybe to a certain point honest.
They're not kind.
Exactly.
You're a scumbag.
Okay, but it's not a
very harsh word, right?
It's not harsh to call somebody a scumbag.
Well, it's not like a swear word,
but it's certainly not a nice
thing to say to someone.
Okay, exactly.
All right, so let's
listen to all these
adjectives that we've
just looked at right now.
Again, in our dialogue.
And then we'll come back
and look at some more phrases.
(upbeat music)
Jim, what's up, man?
Charlie, is that your ride?
It's butt ugly, dude.
Don't be an airhead.
This is a 1969 Chevy Impala.
I just need to fix it up a bit.
In a couple of months,
this baby's gonna be wicked.
Not even, check it out.
Now that's a fresh ride.
Too bad, the driver is a major dweeb.
Anyone can have a car like that
if their daddy's loaded like his.
He's coming his way.
Be cool.
Hey guys, what do you
think of my automobile?
Isn't it bad to the bone?
Word, the ladies are gonna be lining up
to get with you when they see
you driving around in that car.
You really think so?
For sure, awesome.
Psych, you totally fell for it.
You are a real scumbag, Charlie.
When I do the nasty with the prom
queen, we'll see who has a last laugh.
Dude, don't have a cow.
Okay, well, you know
what, Marco, I love the '80s.
I love the language of the '80s.
I love the music of the '80s.
And I'm really loving
these phrases from the '80s.
So why don't we look at
them now in a fluency builder?
Fluency builder.
All right, so I'm fluency builder today.
Let's take a look at these phrases
that you were talking about.
And the first one is very interesting.
So these two guys
that were making fun of
this other person that
was in this nice car,
and he called them a major dweeb.
A major dweeb.
He's a major dweeb.
What a major dweeb.
Now let's break this into two parts first.
Well, let's see what dweeb means.
Well, a dweeb is a very uncool person.
Okay, so kind of similar to a nerd.
Yeah, a small kind of guy with no power.
Okay, he's a dweeb.
Now this word major.
Just means big, really serious.
So it's a way of emphasizing, right?
Yeah, and you can say anything.
You can have a major anything.
Like, I've got a major headache.
All right, I can say I have
a major problem this week.
Okay, so major, a very big problem.
Yep.
Now they're talking
about this really cool car.
And the guy who is a bit of a dweeb,
he said, isn't it bad to the bone?
Bad it to the bone.
It's bad to the bone.
All right, now this is
also part of a famous
song bad to the bone,
but what does it mean?
Well, when something is bad
to the bone, it's super cool.
It's like, it's so
dangerous that it's cool.
Exactly, it's very, very cool.
It's bad to the bone.
Now this is not used anymore.
No, no, no, don't walk out of your
house and use this phrase tomorrow.
All right, so, but it's interesting to
know because there is a famous song
that has this phrase in
it, so bad to the bone.
All right, so the car was so cool.
It was bad to the bone
that all of the ladies
would be wanting
to get with the driver.
All right, so somebody
wants to get with you.
He just wants to get with you.
So if you wanna get with someone,
you wanna have sex with them.
Right, so if you wanna
get with someone, basically,
it means that you want
to have sex with them,
but there's another
phrase that was used in the
dialogue that means
pretty much the same thing.
Yeah, to do the nasty.
To do the nasty.
They're doing the nasty.
Okay, now this was a very
popular way of saying it in the '80s.
It means to have sex as well.
Yeah, but this one is
a little bit rude, isn't it?
Yeah, I think it's a
little bit more direct.
Yeah, if you and your
friends are talking and you say,
hey, I think that girl
wants to get with you,
it's a little bit more
casual and less obvious.
Yeah, yes, do the nasty is a
little bit more, a little more rude.
Yeah, a little bit more direct.
Yeah.
And now the last phrase
that we're gonna look at today
was made famous by the
cartoons, the Simpsons.
And it's don't have a cow.
Don't have a cow.
So to not have a cow,
don't have a cow means
to get really angry, to
freak out, to get upset.
All right, so now we know
that you say don't have a cow,
but can I say it and
use it in the positive?
Can I say, hey, my boss totally
had a cow today in the office?
Yeah, and it means again, so it freaked out,
got angry, made a big deal of something.
Okay, he had a cow.
Yeah, so Frank's gonna have a cow
when he finds out I smashed his car.
Of course, Frank is gonna have a cow.
How can you smash his car?
All right, but now it's time for us to
listen to this dialogue for the last time.
And then we'll come back and talk a little
bit more about this decade of the 1980s.
(upbeat music)
- Jim, what's up, man? - Charlie.
Is that your ride?
It's butt ugly, dude.
(laughs)
- Don't be an airhead.
This is a 1969 Chevy Impala.
I just need to fix it up a bit.
In a couple of months, this
baby is gonna be wicked.
- Not even, check it out.
Now that's a fresh ride.
- Well, too bad, the
driver's a major dweeb.
Anyway, we can have a car like
that if their daddy's loaded like his.
He's coming this way, be cool.
(upbeat music)
- Hey, guys, what do you
think of my automobile?
Isn't it bad to the bone?
- Word.
The ladies are gonna be
lining up to get with you
when they see you
driving around in that car.
- You really think so.
- For sure, awesome.
- Psych, you totally fell for it.
- You're a real scumbag, Charlie.
When I do the nasty with the prom
queen, we'll see who has a last laugh.
- Dude, don't have a cow.
(upbeat music)
Okay, so Marco, when
I was listening to the
dialogue this time, I
heard a really cool word.
They said psych.
- Right, now this was a very popular thing
during the '80s when you
would say to somebody, psych.
So this is like saying,
just kidding, right?
- Just kidding, right?
So you would say, oh
Eric, I really like your hat.
- Oh, thank you.
- Psych, that hat is terrible.
- Oh.
(laughing)
- Right, so that's how you would use it.
- Okay.
- Give somebody a compliment
you would lie to somebody and
then tell them psych and
then like tell them the truth,
like, oh, that hat is terrible
or, oh, I was just kidding.
- Okay, so psych, what a great phrase.
- It was very, very popular.
And when I was in school,
we would use it as well.
We would psych each other out.
- So do we still use this phrase today?
- I don't think we use it today.
I don't think it's cool anymore.
- Well, if you'd use it, it's
kind of like you're joking, right?
- Yeah, and I think it
would make people laugh.
Like, oh, you know, that's pretty funny.
- Yeah, you're joking about
how you're a little bit old fashions.
- Exactly.
I'm very sure you would
surprise a lot of your native
English speaking friends
if you use this phrase.
- A good one to try out.
Now, if you have any questions
about this phrase or any
other of the language, come to
our website at EnglishPod.com.
- Right, we're there
to answer all your
questions and also let
us know any other lessons
or topics that you would like
to learn about in the future.
- Well, thanks for listening
to this lesson, you guys.
And until next time, goodbye.
(upbeat music)